Shubham Shrivastava

Member of Technical Staff - II | React Developer

Phone: 8105595387

Email: shubham.shri1703@gmail.com

Experienced Member Of Technical Staff with history of working with the front-end libraries and frameworks like React, Redux, along with proficiency in JavaScript. Also experienced in writing unit tests for React Applications using libraries like JEST and Enzyme.

SKILLS

React, JavaScript, Redux, HTML5, CSS, SCSS, JEST, Enzyme, Webpack, Docker, Google Firebase

EXPERIENCE

Nineleaps Technology Solutions

Jan 2020 to Present

Member of Technical Staff - ll

- Worked on building complex, scalable React Applications from scratch having multiple user roles.
- Was responsible for taking decisions on which design patterns should be followed in the team.
- Worked on making reusable components having shared data using libraries like Redux.js
- Was responsible for writing unit tests for React applications using libraries like JEST and Enzyme.
- · Worked on increasing the performance of the React applications by using tools like React Profiler, webpack etc.

Nineleaps Technology Solutions

Jul 2019 to Jan 2020

Graduate Intern Trainee

- Worked on building React Applications from scratch, having good user experience, while maintaining the re-usability of code across the codebase.
- Was responsible for following the best practices like separation of concerns, DRY etc. along other best practices related solely
 to react
- Worked with CSS pre-processors like SCSS for developing beautiful and responsive web applications.

PROJECTS

Vencora March 2020 to Present

- Portal to streamline the invoice payment cycle between vendors and the company.
- Involves managing the Purchase Orders, Contracts, Documents and Invoices related to the vendors that can be managed by the admins.
- Technologies Used: <u>Front-end</u>: <u>ReactJs</u>, <u>ReduxJs</u>, <u>Back-End</u>: <u>Springboot</u>

Tegleap Dec 2019 to Feb 2020

- Online Platform developed for smooth on-boarding of new employees that are yet to join the company.
- Involves managing and overlooking full process of on-boarding right from the recruitment of the employee till the time he/she joins the company.
- Technologies Used: <u>Front-end</u>: <u>ReactJs</u>, <u>ReduxJs</u>, <u>Back-End</u>: <u>Springboot</u>

ReimburseMe July 2019 to Nov 2019

- Online Platform developed for making the monthly reimbursement fast and simple.
- Using this, an employee(user) can upload the bills he/she wants to be reimbursed and assign his/her manager(Admin).
 Manager can then approve the bill or reject it. If approved, the bill can later be reimbursed by the finance department employee(Super Admin)
- Technologies Used: Front-end: ReactJs, ReduxJs, Semantic UI, Back-End: Springboot

EDUCATION

BMS Institute of Technology and Management

June 2015 to May 2019

Bachelor of Engineering - BE (Information Science)